Guide to the Rice University Pi Delta Phi records, 1930-2000 UA 247
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Pi Delta Phi records
1930-2000
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Bourgeois, Andre
UA 247
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection consists of membership and financial records of the Theta Chapter of Pi Delta Phi, the National French Honor Society, from 1930 through 2000. There are yearly membership lists, records of dues received and expenditures made. Initiation programs are also included, as are records of donations that established the André Bourgeois Pi Delta Phi Award in 1994.
Biographical / Historical
The Theta Chapter of Pi Delta Phi, the National French Honor Society, was established at Rice University in 1930. From that time on, initiation of new members took place every year in April. The ceremony was traditionally followed by a banquet at the Faculty Club. Officers were elected at each year's annual meeting.
The first advisor was Professor Marcel Moraud. He was succeeded in 1956 by Professor Andre Bourgeois, who in turn was succeeded by Dr. Margaret Sobel in 1971. It is not clear when this role passed to Professor Deborah Nelson, but she was serving as advisor in the later years of the records.
When Professor Bourgeois died in 1994, donations in his memory were used to establish an award given annually, the André Bourgeois Pi Delta Phi Award.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records of the Theta Chapter of the National French Honor Society, Pi Delta Phi, at Rice University, established in 1930. A leather-covered loose leaf album holds membership and financial records from 1930 through 1971. Similar records from 1972 through 2000 are contained in labeled folders. Also included are initiation programs and records of donations to the André Bourgeois Pi Delta Phi Award fund established with memorial gifts at his death in 1994.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to the Woodson Research Center circa 2005.
Index Terms
Subjects
Rice University -- History
Document Types
directories; programs (documents); financial records
- Series I: Membership rosters and initiation programs, 207724
  - Membership rosters 1996-2000 and blank stationery, 207725 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Initiation programs, 207726 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Financial records, 207723
  - Banking documents 1971-1979, 207727 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Banking documents 1980-1995, 207728 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Banking documents 1996-2000, 207729 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - I.R.S. Applications for Employer Identification Number 1984-1988, 207730 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Deposit booklets and Passbooks 1962-1990, 207731 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Records of Donations to the André Bourgeois Pi Delta Phi Award Fund, 207732 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Expense Account book 1977-1981, 207733 (Box 1, Folder -)
  - Leather covered loose leaf album of records from 1930 through 1971, 207734 (Box 1, Folder -)